<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Machine Learning 1DL034 on Introduction to ML 1D034 homepage.</title>
    <link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction to Machine Learning 1DL034 on Introduction to ML 1D034 homepage.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/lectures/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author>
      <guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/lectures/index.html</guid>
      <description>Here you can find information on the lectures, as well as information on when you should have enough information to be able to attempt the various practical and theoretical python notebook assignments. The project should be started as soon as possible, and you should try different machine learning algorithms on the data set as you learn them in the course.
There is a menu item for each lecture where you can find a reading guide for the textbook, links to additional material and links to slides.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information on the Assignments</title>
      <link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/labs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author>
      <guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/labs/index.html</guid>
      <description>Assignment This course has four theoretical and four practical assignments that are Python notebooks that you should complete. The practical notebooks introduce you to tools such as pandas, NumPy and scikit-learn. The theoretical notebooks help you to deepen you knowledge of some of the topics covered in the course.
The assignments are available publicly on github.
Project The project will be hosted on kaggle and will only available to students registered on the course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended Textbooks and Links</title>
      <link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author>
      <guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s material. Andrew Ng is one of the giants in machine learning. He has written numerous very important papers, and it one of the founders of Coursera.
He has made of videos on machine learning of various formats. He is a far better lecturer than me, and his lectures will be of much higher quality than I can record. Some of his lectures are on a whiteboard and some of them are him talking over his slides.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>