<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recommended Textbooks and Links :: 1DL034</title><link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.html</link><description>Course Text books and other material Creating Python Virtual Environments This assumes that you are a command line person and are running Linux or MacOS. Using Python Notebooks This assumes that you are a command line person and are running Linux or MacOS. Some hints for Windows users</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><managingEditor>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</managingEditor><webMaster>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recommended Books and other study material</title><link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/books_and_online/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/books_and_online/index.html</guid><description>All the material in this course is standard material. There are a lot of books on machine learning, some more theoretical and some more practical. It is difficult to recommend a book that fits the background for all students on this course. Some books are too mathematical and some books are too practical. The course has two recommended text books. One is more theoretical, and one is more hands on with Python. Both of them cover most of the material in the course.</description></item><item><title>Creating and using Python Virtual Environments</title><link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/python_virtual_env/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/python_virtual_env/index.html</guid><description>Windows users These instructions are mostly for Linux or MacOS. If you are windows there are other options such as AnaConda. You also have problems with integrating with various windows IDEs. If you are using windows then maybe these instructions are useful.
In a lot of my courses I encourage students to use python virtual environments. Virtual environments are a great way of making sure that you have the correct version of packages installed. This is very short cheat sheet on how to set them up. I will assume that we are using python 3. Luckily python 3 has virtual environments set up. It is all in the documentation, but then sometimes people are too lazy to google, or do not know what to google for.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Python notebooks locally for Machine Learning</title><link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/python_notebooks_ml/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/python_notebooks_ml/index.html</guid><description>While there are many options for hosting python notebooks for free remotely, but I prefer to do things locally. If you wish to do the same then please read on. Note that I did home some problems installing skikit-image on a new Apple with M1 silicon, but after upgrading the latest version of the operating system and doing and updating my homebrew setup everything works. Note that these instructions are for using pip. If you are using an alternative package manager such as Anaconda then you are on your own. I know nothing about setting up Python on a windows machine.</description></item><item><title>Using Anaconda with Windows.</title><link>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/anaconda_instructions/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>justin.pearson@it.uu.se (Justin Pearson)</author><guid>https://intro-ml-1dl034-uu-se.github.io/resources/anaconda_instructions/index.html</guid><description>Disclaimer These instructions come with no warranty. I do not use Windows. If you have any questions about Windows then I cannot answer them. If you have any constructive comments the please contact me.
Anaconda is a distribution of Python and R that includes many popular Data Science packages, such as Jupyter Notebook, NumPy, pandas, and scikit-learn. For numerous reasons, it is suggested for working with Jupyter Notebook.</description></item></channel></rss>